Kevin Dawe

Full Stack Developer

kevin.dawe@gmail.com | kevindawe.ca | github.com/kld87

London, Ontario, CA | Remote

About

Passionate techie and dedicated Full Stack Developer with 10+ years of experience in the industry. Served as product owner, team leader, and senior developer for SaaS-based web applications. Possesses a broad skill set including programming, sysadmin, devops, IT security, and scaling infrastructure for a rapidly growing company. Favours Test-Driven-Development and maintainable code suited for a long support horizon.

Currently seeking interesting opportunities in the tech sector in the application development and systems space.

Primary Skills

Front-end: HTML/CSS/JS, SASS, JQuery, Angular, AngularJS, Bootstrap, OpenLayers

Back-end: PHP (5, 7, and HHVM), PHPUnit, GeoServer

Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, PostGIS, Redis

Devops: Atlassian Products (JIRA, BitBucket, Bamboo, Confluence), git, SVN, grunt, npm, Bower,

Vagrant, Composer

Other: Linux server admin, network admin (subnetting, VLANs, routing, VPNs), IT Security, Apache & nginx configuration, shell scripting, cURL, VirtualBox, HYPER-V, Ubiquiti, VOIP (Avaya),

QGIS, Neural Networks

Additional Experience With

Java & JUnit, Python, Google & Twitter APIs, Leaflet, Node.js, websockets, Windows Server administration, VMWare, Digital Ocean, ESRI, Adobe Flex

Work Experience

PSD Research, Consulting, and Software - http://psdrcs.com

Senior Full Stack Developer, Systems Administrator Full-Time, London ON, 2010 - Aug. 2019

Part-Time, Remote, 2006 - 2010

- Product owner, team leader, and lead developer on various asset management, financial, and geospatial SaaS applications for the Canadian public sector market
- Coded primarily in PHP, PostgreSQL, AngularJS, and Bootstrap
- Developed various scripts and 3rd-party integrations with client systems

- Performed code review, caught SQL injection, CSRF, and directory transversal vulnerabilities before they were added to the code base
- First developer hired, helped grow the company to 75+ employees with over 250 municipal clients across Canada
- Development work led to successful application for Scientific Research and Experimental Development (SR&ED) tax credits over multiple years
- Responsible for sysadmin, including multiple on-prem Ubuntu Linux servers (production and internal), network infrastructure (including remote sites), and an Avaya VOIP system
- Responsible for devops, including administration of self-hosted Atlassian products (JIRA, BitBucket, Bamboo, Confluence) including a build/testing server, data migration, and deployment procedures`
- Organized and ran programming challenges for the development group
- Assisted HR with interviewing candidates and technical screening

Scotiabank

Security Research Intern

Scarborough ON, Sept. 2009 - Apr. 2010

- Researched hardware & software security solutions for potential use within the organization
- Organized and managed a team consisting of four other interns
- Evaluated and tested security claims of potential solutions
- Collaborated with vendors to acquire necessary product information and demonstrations
- Compiled reports and recommendations based on project results that were then presented to upper management

Atec Computer Systems

Web Application Developer

Part-Time, Remote, 2006 - 2008

- Developed web applications primarily based in PHP & MySQL for clients
- Designed and implemented inventory management, electronic document management, and image gallery applications
- Created automated email-based notification systems
- Installed and managed a LAMP server and several associated domains

Winspear Homes

Web Developer

Part-Time, Smithville ON, 2004 - 2007

- Created a showcase website for a local housing developer
- Hosted pictures and floor plans for available units
- Provisioned and managed a self-hosted Linux + Apache server for the site
- Successfully migrated project to a shared hosting provider upon completion

Education

Ontario Tech University (formerly UOIT)

Bachelor of Information Technology (Honours) Network Security Specialization Oshawa ON, 2006 - 2010

Hobbies & Interests

- Anything tech/gaming related
- Reading Sci-Fi
- Playing banjo
- Squash
- Cooking

References

Available upon request